Muhammed Asarudheen

Sales And Operations Executive

Objectives

proficient and highly knowledgeable Sales Executive with Engineering graduation and 3 year track record of sales success. Motivated professional who excels at delivering quality service while Looking to take next step in a challenging discipline dedicated to delivering high quality service in which i can utilize and build upon my current knowledge and there by approaching a positive growth for my career along with cherished reputation of the organization.

Strengths

- Ambitious and highly motivated to meet the demands of the job.
- Motivational and engaging style
- Flexible, energetic, and capable of making sound project decisions.
- Specializes in developing innovative sales methods that exceed customer expectations.
- · Previous experience working in competitive markets and delivering results.

Experience

Jul 2018 - present

Sales & Operations Executive

Global Line Services W.L.L

Responsibilities

- · Receiving and responding to approvals and notifications.
- Negotiating the terms of a sales agreement and closing sales.
- Performed at handling customer complaints in a professional efficient manner.
- Representing the company in various exhibitions and trade fairs.
- Communicates with other departments, sales and marketing to effectively plan and distribute the workload.
- Provide presentable communications with clients.
- · Desired level of service in answering their queries.
- Check on the performance of the operations of both internal service providers and external service providers.

Jul 2016 -Apr 2018

Automotive Sales and Marketing Executive.

Nexa Bangalore (Suzuki)

<u>Responsibilities</u>

- Adding value to the car showroom environment.
- Assisting customers to select a vehicle by asking them questions and then listening carefully to their answers.
- Keeping display materials up to date and Coordinated between customer and service technician for auto repairs
- Qualify and follow up on warm Internet leads regarding new and pre-owned vehicle availability, price, and options.
- Solve customer complaints, regarding their vehicle, with solutions assuring customer satisfaction.
- Worked to ensure customer satisfaction and handled customer issues.
- Representing the company at trade exhibitions, events and demonstrations.
- Maintain contact with customers via email, phone calls, and regular updates on promotional offers.
- · Maintaining up to date knowledge of all new vehicle makes and models.



Personal Info

Address

Door No: 22

Bldg 122, Block 326

Road 351, Adliya

Kingdom Of Bahrain

Phone

+973 3465 4326

E-mail

asarudheen.muhd@gmail.com

Date of birth

13 Jun 1995

Citizenship

Indian

Key Skills

Good Sales Skills – Effective, Persistent Negotiator Determined To Close Sales Deals And After Sales.

Basic software such Catia, Auto-CAD, Microsoft Office applications. and Good at computers and the Internet.

Active Listening and Email Management.

Achieving Results and identifying target audience.

Ability to work in fast-paced environments.

Jun 2014 -

Jul 2014

Quality Engineer Trainee (Internship)

Sundaram Clayton Limited. Chennai

http://www.sundaram-clayton.com/

Responsibilities

- Assisted the technical staff of engineers and designers.
- Directed a large group of employees engaged in the specialized tasks.
- Devised tests which answer questions from clients and other engineers on the development of the product.

Education

Aug 2012 -Jun 2016

Bachelor Of Technology in Automotive engineering, SRM Institute of Science and Technology (Chennai)

- Completed German phase language 1 and 2 (A1&A2 German phase)
- Represented the university for inter-college and inter-university sports fests.
- Part of the National Cadet Corps http://nccindia.nic.in/en

Project

Sep 2015 -May 2016

Vehicular Occupant Asphyxiation Detection And Prevention System

Submitted In Partial Fulfillment For The Award Of The Degree of Bachelor Of Technology In Automotive Engineering

An air quality sensor monitors the level of various harmful gases inside the cabin at all times and provides this data to the microcontroller. It ends up being a compact addition the vehicle while also staying cost effective and does the intended purpose in the simplest manner possible without interfering into any of the main electrical parts of the vehicle.

Interests And Hobbies

Automotive and Fitness Enthusiast.

Interested In Giving And Receiving Effective Feedback About Automotive Vehicles.

Formula 1 Follower, Rally Cars And Cafe Racer.

Fantasy Football and Gaming.

Soccer Football And Long Standing Arsenal Supporter.

Beginner Automotive Embedded Design Engineering and Good at Basic Coding Such As C, C++ And Arduino Programming

Languages Known

English



Malayalam (Mother tongue)



German (Completed German Phase A1 and A2)

